A growth of 15% has been seen. Actually, the
story seems to be building from the premium figures of insurance companies that have come in May. So,
how are the growth numbers looking exactly? What is fueling the
story of ICICI Lombard
and how is the performance of its other peer set?
We have Yash with us who closely tracks this sector.
Yash, tell us what is happening
here Harshita. The difference between yesterday and today is
that we are talking about general pick up from life
and secondly we are talking about business reform from regulatory reform. The
premium growth numbers of general insurance of May, which
come every month, have been released. If we
talk about the industry, the
consistent growth of 15% has been maintained for a long time.
15% standalone health
insurance companies, which do only health
insurance, saw a growth of 26%
in their premium collection in the month of May
on a year on year basis.
If you ask me which
company was the best performer, I would say ICICI Lombard. There was a
very strong performance in the month of May.
In the month of 2024, i.e. last month
also, the industry had a very strong performance.
As I said,
ICICI Lombard has
grown its premium by 22% in both April and May.
This means that the first
two months of the financial year have been
very strong. For ICICI Lombard, the
market share, if seen together for April and
May
2024, has improved by
60 basis points.
In ICICI Lombard, the premium
growth has also been strong and there has been an
improvement of 60 basis points i.e. 6%. Talking about the next company
which was recently listed, Go
Digit General Insurance, there has been a
growth of 36% in premium up to May,
i.e. there has been a
growth of 19% in premium in the financial year. The market share has improved by 11%.
New India Assurance
is in a problematic zone for the company because the
premium growth of the company has been running at a very slow pace for a long time.  Yes,
in the month of May, the premium contracted
by about 1% and in UptoMe, the same
premium increased by only 2%. But the
biggest concern for New India Assurance is that if we
look at the market share of UptoMe, it has contracted by 192 basis
points, that is, by almost 2%.
Finally, the
makeup premium of Star Health Insurance
increased by 16% and UptoMe premium
increased by 19%. If we
look at the market share of Star Health among all the general insurance
companies, it
saw an increase of 14 basis points and if we look at the market share of Star Health
among all the standalone health insurance companies, then
there is concern for the company
because we saw the market share decreasing by 250 basis points.
Okay, so this is in fact 4 points.
Clearly, it has
emerged as an outperformer. Thank you Yash for this update,
Dharmesh. This entire pocket
was actually in focus this week, as Yash was also mentioning,
yesterday we were talking about regulatory
reforms, today of course  We are seeing
how the business appears to be growing,
but insurance is such a space where
I remember whenever HDFC Life and SBI
Life were listed, everyone used to
say in one voice that big money will be made here,
money has been made, but will it be seen growing now?
Should there be some exposure to these stocks this year?
Absolutely Harshita, but I
will defer to stock picks because if you
look at SDSC Life, SBI Life or ICC Prudential Life,
in the last 8-10 years since their listing, their CAGR has
not been above 89. They have
not been able to gain much traction in terms of profitability, whereas their valuation multiple has
always been of growth. If we
talk in terms of a P ratio, then
their P multiple is around 70-80 and
if you look at the return on equity,
none of these three is more than 10-11,
but in comparison to this, Life Insurance
Corporation of India gives a
return on equity and return on
capital employed of around 60 per plus and their PAT
growth  The Kager is also trading at similar 10-11, it is
available at a multiple of 15, so at
almost 1% of the valuation, this company
is available to you with strong cash flow and its
market share is still 1%.
Talking about new business premium,
in the last quarter they had grown there at 14% as well,
so I feel that
in such an environment when the market is very heated,
some margin of safety should be looked at.
We had included Life Insurance Corporation in the theme play of our budget and
kept it in T, so
you can invest there as a systematic investment
and if you want to buy
from general insurance, then
I feel a little comfortable with GIC R also, although the
insurance play is fundamentally quite sound,
you see some comfort there too,
so we have advised our clients to buy these two companies from the insurance sector
and recommend them to keep
aggregating it in the portfolio and keep accumulating it in the
meantime.